Guide to the Mary E. Gawthorpe Papers TAM.275
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Mary E. Gawthorpe Papers
1881-1990
1907-1933
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Gawthorpe, Mary Eleanor, 1881-1973
Crocker, Anne Ward
Miessner, Elizabeth Ward
Ward, Joyce Cover
TAM.275
9.75 Linear Feet in 7 record cartons, 3 oversize flat boxes, 1 photograph box, 11 folders in shared boxes, and 1 flat file drawer
Mary E. Gawthorpe (1881-1973) was a British suffragist who was an organizer for the Women's Social and Political Union (WSPU) from 1906 to 1912. Following her immigration to the United States in 1916, she was involved in a number of American social and political movements, including women's suffrage and labor education. Her papers, which consist of diaries, correspondence, notes, postcards, flyers, leaflets, news clippings, and photographs, cover the period of her involvement with the radical British suffragettes as well as some of her activities in the United States.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into six series:
I: Diaries/Engagement Books, 1918-1972
II: Correspondence, 1903-1973
III: Subject Files, 1881-1990
IV: Educational Materials and Notes, circa 1890-1932
V: Postcards, 1903-1970
VI: Photographs, Graphic Materials, and Artifacts, 1900-circa 1950s
Series I is arranged chronologically. Series II is arranged alphabetically by correspondent. Series III, IV, and VI are arranged alphabetically by folder title. Series V is arranged chronologically within two sections, Suffrage and General.
Biographical Note
Mary Eleanor Gawthorpe (1881-1973) was born in Leeds, England, on January 12, 1881, to John and Annie Eliza (Mountain) Gawthorpe. She had four siblings, but only one sister, Annie Gatenby, and a brother, James Arthur, survived to adulthood. Her father was a leather worker, and her mother worked occasionally as a textile worker and laundress to help support the family. Gawthorpe became a pupil-teacher at age thirteen in a local church school. Following her certification, she served as a schoolteacher in Leeds until 1906.
While she was studying and teaching, Gawthorpe became involved in socialist and labor politics in Leeds through her friend Tom Garrs. She was active in the Independent Labour Party (ILP) and the Women's Labour League, and she coordinated a women's page in the local Labour News. Through this work she began to speak in public, and the first two speeches she prepared were entitled "The Child under Socialism" and "The Modern Pariah, a plea against the making of criminals." She was also a leading figure of the Leeds branch of the National Union of Teachers, served on the Lord Mayor of Leeds Committee for the Feeding of School Children, and was active in A.R. Orage's Leeds Arts Club.
Christabel Pankhurst had been speaking to ILP audiences throughout England, and Gawthorpe became increasingly interested in the issue of women's suffrage, particularly after the arrest of Christable Pankhurst and Annie Kenney at Free Trade Hall in Manchester. Though the Women's Social and Political Union (WSPU) was active at that time only in Manchester and other Lancashire towns, Gawthorpe began to organize suffrage-related events in her native Leeds and throughout Yorkshire by writing letters to the editor and speaking at local labor events. She helped Isabella Ford form the Leeds Suffrage Society, which was affiliated with the National Union of Women's Suffrage Societies. In 1906, she resigned her teaching post at the Bramley Council School to devote more time to these causes, and later that year, she accepted an offer to become a full-time organizer for the WSPU. As she became more involved with the militant suffragettes, she grew less active in the ILP.
One of her first assignments was to join Christabel Pankhurst in Wales, where she drew upon her own working-class background and involvement in the labor movement to organize mining communities for the Mid-Glamorgan campaign against the Liberal politician Samuel Evans. Gawthorpe became one of the WSPU's primary speakers, and was especially active in the North of England. She was first arrested for disrupting a House of Commons meeting on October 23, 1906. She was known as a particularly dynamic and persuasive orator, and was one of the speakers at a Hyde Park demonstration that drew over 200,000 people. By 1909, she was head organizer for the Lancashire branch of the WSPU, headquartered in Manchester. Several imprisonments, which included hunger strikes and forced feedings, eroded her already fragile health, and she had to drop out of the movement for repeated periods of convalescence. In 1910, she was unable to be in Manchester to fulfill her duties for the Autumn Campaign, but conducted a "bed-side" effort to raise money to support the campaign. She joined with Dora Marsden in 1911 in a venture to start a new journal, The Freewoman, which sometimes found itself at odds with WSPU leaders, including the Pankhursts. In 1912, the issue of forced feeding of suffragette prisoners became increasingly important to her, and she led a petition drive in protest of the practice (which generated a lengthy response from George Bernard Shaw). She also made an unsuccessful call in this year for a national women's hunger strike.
Following 1912, Gawthorpe's health was too poor to continue her participation in the movement. She spent time in different locales to recover, including a trip to Italy in 1914-15. She intermittently received financial support from individual suffragettes until 1916. Around this time, she began to consider other fields of work she could pursue. She took a secretarial training course at Kensington College in 1915.
Gawthorpe traveled to the United States with her mother in 1916, where they joined family members in Monroe, New York. While it appears that Gawthorpe initially advertised herself for employment as an editor's or author's assistant, she soon began to work as an organizer for a number of political causes and moved from campaign to campaign for the next several years. She quickly joined the American struggle for women's suffrage, working first as a Field Organizer and then Head Organizer for the Brooklyn branch of the New York State Woman Suffrage Party. Mary Ogden White wrote of her contribution to this movement, "Miss Gawthorpe is a morsel of a woman to have achieved so much, but one look into her hazel eyes--her very unusual hazel eyes--is convincing of the power within her. She is all fire and quick response, a flash of energy, of sympathy, of comprehension." In February 1917, she went to Buffalo to work as chairperson of the Western New York Suffrage News Service. In this capacity, she led one contingent of a caravan to the Suffragists' State Convention, led by Gertrude Franchot Tone in August 1917. Later that year, she was appointed State Press Chairman for the Party, a capacity in which she served until mid-1918.
Following her work with the Woman Suffrage Party, Gawthorpe worked on a number of short-term organizing projects around the country. In 1918, she worked for the National Consumers League's Industrial Investigation. Gawthorpe assisted in the completion of the League's study of "Woman's Work in Wartime" in Wilmington, Delaware. Gawthorpe carried out research by visiting homes to gather family history and budget data and then remained to serve as Legislative Secretary of the Delaware Consumers' League, working on their campaign for a Minimum Wage Law.
In 1919, she traveled to Chicago, where she worked with the Cook County Labor Party, especially with the Women's Section. She continued the public speaking for which she had been well known in the British suffrage movement, and was a Labor Day speaker at a demonstration of miners in Belleville, Illinois. It may have been in Chicago that she became associated with Sidney Hillman's Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America, as her next move was to Rochester, where she briefly served as the union's Director of Educational Programs. She was a delegate to the national convention of the National Labor Party (later the Farmer-Labor Party) in Chicago in 1920, and was "loaned" by ACWA to work on the presidential campaign of Parley Parker Christensen. To aid the campaign, she spoke in the mining districts of Indiana and Illinois. From 1921-1922, she was an executive secretary for the League for Mutual Aid.
In 1921, she married John Sanders, an engineer who had been a boarder in the home of her brother, James Arthur, in Newark, New Jersey, where the family had relocated. The couple moved to Whitestone, New York, where they resided for the rest of their lives. Following her marriage, Gawthorpe held no "official job"--as she described--but maintained close associations with a number of progressive and labor organizations around New York City, particularly the New School for Social Research.
In 1931, Gawthorpe once again became involved with her acquaintances from the British suffrage movement when she began to promote Sylvia Pankhurst's book, The Suffragette Movement, which was experiencing poor sales in the United States. This endeavor led to a disagreement with Pankhurst over a description of Gawthorpe in a brief footnote in the book, which overlooked Gawthorpe's involvement in the women's suffrage movement in the United States following her emigration. To set the record straight, and to provide detailed information about her activities in the United States for a compilation of biographies of militant suffragettes for the Suffragette Fellowship in Britain, she solicited letters of reference from a number of political figures with whom she had worked, including Gertrude Franchot Tone, Roger Baldwin, Arthur Garfield Hays, and Vera B. Whitehouse. Gawthorpe eventually demanded that Pankhurst produce a second edition of the book in order to correct the mistake, an action Pankhurst was not prepared to take. Following a contentious correspondence from 1931 to 1935, they appear to have fallen out of touch.
In 1962, Gawthorpe wrote a memoir of her early years and her participation in the British suffrage movement, Up Hill to Holloway, printed by Traversity Press of Penobscot, Maine. John Sanders passed away the following year. In addition to her political activities, Gawthorpe maintained interests in astrology, gardening, painting, and drawing. She was moved to the Clearview Nursing Home in Whitestone, New York, in January 1973, and passed away there on March 12, 1973. She was survived by her nephew and heir, Sidney John Ward, whose daughters preserved her papers and donated them to the Tamiment Library.
Sources:
Diane Atkinson, The Suffragettes in Pictures (London: Sutton Publishing Limited, 1996).
Mary Gawthorpe, Up Hill to Holloway (Penobscot, Maine: Traversity Press, 1962).
Sandra Holton, Suffrage Days: Stories from the Women's Suffrage Movement (London: Routledge, 1996).
Pankhurst, Sylvia, The Suffragette Movement; An Intimate Account of Persons and Ideals (London: Longmans, Green, and Co., 1931).
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Anne Ward Crocker, Elizabeth Ward Miessner, and Joyce Cover Ward in 2001. The accession numbers related to this gift are 2001.028 and 2001.183.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
This collection, with the exception of some parts of Boxes 4 and 5 and some of the photographs, is available on microfilm (Film R-7264) for use in this repository only. The publishers of the microfilm edition excluded a small number of documents from these boxes, mainly concerning family history, because of privacy considerations. Researchers must use microfilm for this collection except for Boxes 4 and 5 and the photographs, at the discretion of the reference archivist. There is also a guide to the microfilm available at the Tamiment Library (call number REF HQ1413.G39 A3 2006).
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Some items, specifically the "Self Denial" sash in boxes 10-11 are extremely fragile; researchers must consult the photograph of the object.
Related Material
The Dora Marsden Papers, housed in the Manuscripts Division of the Department of Rare Books and Special Collections at Princeton University, contain an extensive amount of correspondence between Marsden and Gawthorpe. The Suffragette Fellowship Collection at the Museum of London also contains materials related to Gawthorpe's work with the Women's Social and Political Union.
Scope and Content Note
The collection is predominantly comprised of materials related to Gawthorpe's work as a suffragist, including her involvement with the Women's Social and Political Union (WSPU) and other pro-suffrage groups during the early 20th century. Genres of materials that document Gawthorpe's activism include correspondence and postcards; diaries and engagement books; notes; and news clippings, flyers, programs, leaflets, pamphlets, and other forms of printed ephemera. These materials also reflect the wider activities of many of the era's pro- and anti-suffrage groups and the work of other suffragettes like the Pankhursts. To a lesser extent, the collection provides insight into Gawthorpe's interest in the labor movement, her teaching career, and her personal life.
Separated Material
A copy of Gawthorpe's autobiography, Up Hill to Holloway, and its accompanying index/supplement were separated for library cataloging, as were approximately ten other books related to women's suffrage and other topics. A number of suffrage-themed journals which were originally processed as part of the collection were separated in 2013 and also designated for library cataloging.
Women -- Suffrage -- New York (State); Photographs.; Correspondence.; Postcards.; Women -- Suffrage; Pamphlets.; Women -- Suffrage -- Great Britain; Women in the labor movement -- United States; Leaflets (printed works); Women's Social and Political Union (Great Britain); Baldwin, Roger Nash, 1884-1981; Blackwell, Alice Stone, 1857-1950; Pankhurst, E. Sylvia (Estelle Sylvia), 1882-1960.; Women's Labour League; Blatch, Harriot Stanton, 1856-1940; Gawthorpe, Mary Eleanor, 1881-1973; Beffel, John Nicholas; Paul, Alice, 1885-1977.; Shaw, Bernard, 1856-1950.; Nearing, Scott, 1883-1983.; Tone, Franchot.; Tone, Gertrude Franchot.; Crocker, Anne Ward; Miessner, Elizabeth Ward; Ward, Joyce Cover
- Series I: Diaries, 1918-1972; 61641
  Scope and Content Note
  Gawthorpe recorded her activities in engagement books from shortly after her arrival in the United States until her death. These materials do not provide a comprehensive account of Gawthorpe's activities from this period, however, because the detail of her accounts varied greatly from year to year.
  - Diaries/Engagement Books, 1918-1920; 61665 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Diaries/Engagement Books, 1920-1925; 61664 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Diaries/Engagement Books, 1926-1929; 61663 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Diaries/Engagement Books, 1930-1935; 61662 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Diaries/Engagement Books, 1936-1938; 61661 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Diaries/Engagement Books, 1939-1940; 61660 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Diaries/Engagement Books, 1941-1942; 61659 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Diaries/Engagement Books, 1943-1945; 61658 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Diaries/Engagement Books, 1946-1947; 61657 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Diaries/Engagement Books, 1948-1949; 61656 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Diaries/Engagement Books, 1950-1951; 61655 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Diaries/Engagement Books, 1952-1953; 61654 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Diaries/Engagement Books, 1954-1955; 61653 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Diaries/Engagement Books, 1956-1957; 61652 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Diaries/Engagement Books, 1958-1959; 61651 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Diaries/Engagement Books, 1960-1961; 61650 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Diaries/Engagement Books, 1962; 61649 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Diaries/Engagement Books, 1963; 61648 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Diaries/Engagement Books, 1964; 61647 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Diaries/Engagement Books, 1965; 61646 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Diaries/Engagement Books, 1966-1967; 61645 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Diaries/Engagement Books, 1968-1969; 61644 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Diaries/Engagement Books, 1970-1971; 61643 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Diaries/Engagement Books, 1972; 61642 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Series II: Correspondence, 1930-1973; 61471
  This series contains Gawthorpe's incoming and outgoing correspondence. Much of the correspondence from 1931 to 1933 concerns the publication of Sylvia Pankhurst's book The Suffragette Movement and a dispute between the two women over Pankhurst's treatment of Gawthorpe's American career in a footnote. Pankhurst's refusal to revise the book seems to have led to the end of their correspondence. Material pertaining to this matter can be found throughout this series. Among the correspondents on this topic are: John Beffel, Harriet Stanton Blatch, Alice Stone Blackwell, Parley Parker Christensen, Mary E. Dreier, John Galsworthy, Victor Gollancz, Arthur Garfield Hays, A.R. Orage, Sylvia Pankhurst, Alice Paul, Emmeline Pethick-Lawrence, George Bernard Shaw, and Gertrude Franchot Tone. (See also Pankhurst files in Series III.)
  Another key issue addressed in this series is the split between Gawthorpe and Dora Marsden, who briefly co-edited The Freewoman in 1911. This issue is addressed in the correspondence with Albert and Adele Lowy and Grace Jardine.
  Other correspondents of note in this series are Scott Nearing, Roger Baldwin, Gertrude Franchot Tone, and Havelock Ellis. This series also includes five folders of cards from Gawthorpe's husband, John Sanders.
  - Unidentified, undated, 1903-1933, 1968-1972; 61640 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - A, undated, 1911-1923; 61639 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Amberg, Ruth, undated, 1922; 61638 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Armstrong, E. Noel, undated, 1926-1935; 61637 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Astrological Research Foundation, 1930-1931, 1931; 61636 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - B, undated, 1915-1933, 1969; 61635 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Baldwin, Roger, undated, 1920-1933; 61634 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Barker, E. Frye, 1925-1927, 1927; 61633 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Barney, Nora Stanton, 1926; 61632 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Becker, Maurice, undated, 1920-1933; 61631 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Beckwith, Ella G., undated, 1920; 61630 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Beekman, Henry R., 1928; 61629 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Beffel, John, 1933; 61628 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Berrien, Laura M., 1931; 61627 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Blackwell, Alice Stone, 1931; 61626 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Blatch, Harriet Stanton, undated, 1931; 61625 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Bosworth, Grace M., 1931; 61624 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Bradley, Ivah, 1932; 61623 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Broun, Heyword, 1933; 61622 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Byrns, Elinor, 1921-1922, 1922; 61621 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - C, undated, 1919-1933; 61620 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Carpenter, Edward, 1915; 61619 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Carson, Frank, undated, 1926-1933; 61618 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Carus, Helena Proudfoot, 1919-1949, 1949; 61617 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Cathcart, Vera Countess of, 1926; 61616 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Christensen, Parley Parker, 1924, 1931; 61615 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Civic Club, 1926-1927; 61614 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Condon, Mollie, 1925-1933; 61613 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Consolidated Edison, 1939; 61612 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Corio, Sylvio, 1931-1936; 61611 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Crossley, Stella, 1925-1926; 61610 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - D, undated, 1914-1916; 61609 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Dockray, Leslie, 1970-1972; 61608 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Dreier, Mary E., undated, 1926-1931; 61607 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - E, undated, 1925-1931; 61606 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Ellis, Havelock, 1912; 61605 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - F, undated, 1915-1933; 61604 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Floyd, Louise Adams, undated, 1926-1951; 61603 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Flynn, Elizabeth Gurley, 1930; 61602 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Forbes-Robertson, Sir Johnston, 1910; 61601 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Forward, 1932; 61600 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Frank, Walter and Eva, 1931-1933; 61599 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Fraser, Helen, 1923-1931; 61598 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Freeman, Elisabeth, undated, 1923-1933; 61597 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - G, undated, 1917-1934; 61596 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Galsworthy, John, 1931; 61595 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Garland, Marie Tudor, undated, 1922-1939; 61594 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Garland, Marie Tudor, 1940-1950; 61593 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Garland, Mary Wrenn, 1924-1927; 61592 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Gawthorpe, Annie Eliza, 1910-1919; 61591 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Gawthorpe, James Arthur, 1913; 61590 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Gollancz, Victor, 1931; 61589 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Grant, Myron L., undated, 1933; 61588 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Granville-Smith, Jessica, undated, 1929-1931, 1968-1969; 61587 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Greenbie, Marjorie, 1968-1970; 61586 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Gumberg, Alex, 1931; 61585 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Gunner, Jocelyn, 1927-1949; 61584 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Guthrie, Lillian, 1960-1973; 61583 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Gye, Elsa, 1932; 61582 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - H, undated, 1908-1933, 1970; 61581 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Haapenen, John, 1932; 61580 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Harmati, Sandor, 1932; 61579 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Hays, Aline D., 1931-1933; 61578 (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Hays, Arthur Garfield, 1931-1933; 61577 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Hillman, Sidney, 1920; 61576 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Hollister, Carroll, undated, 1929-1922, 1969; 61575 (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Horst, Gertrude, 1933; 61574 (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Hulburd, Anna K., 1924-1927; 61573 (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Hulst, Cornelia, 1919-1926; 61572 (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - I, ca.1932; 61571 (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Iliff, J.G., 1916; 61570 (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Irwin, Inez Haynes, 1931-1933; 61569 (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - J, undated, 1920-1933; 61568 (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - Jardine, Grace, 1931-1932; 61567 (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - K, undated, 1970; 61566 (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - Kallen, H.M., 1931; 61565 (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - Kelly, Herbert, undated; 61564 (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - Kemp, Eleanor C., 1931; 61563 (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - Kennan, Ellen A., 1926-1933; 61562 (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - L, undated, 1931-1932; 61561 (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - Laski, Harold J., 1931; 61560 (Box 3, Folder 81)
  - LeGallienne, Eva, 1927; 61559 (Box 3, Folder 82)
  - Leslie, Kenneth, undated, 1969; 61558 (Box 3, Folder 83)
  - Levinson, Polly, 1931-1933; 61557 (Box 3, Folder 84)
  - Lidderdale, Jane, 1966-1967; 61556 (Box 3, Folder 85)
  - Lowy, Albert and Adele, 1931, 1971-1972; 61555 (Box 3, Folder 86)
  - Lowy, Mary, 1921; 61554 (Box 3, Folder 87)
  - M, 1910-1933; 61553 (Box 3, Folder 88)
  - MacDonald, Ishbel, 1927; 61552 (Box 3, Folder 89)
  - Manship, Ruth, undated, 1929-1932; 61551 (Box 3, Folder 90)
  - Marble, Mary Flowers, undated, 1927; 61550 (Box 3, Folder 91)
  - Morris, Mary, 1929-1930; 61549 (Box 3, Folder 92)
  - Murray, Stella Wolfe, 1931; 61548 (Box 3, Folder 93)
  - Musgrave, Helen, undated, 1928-1930; 61547 (Box 3, Folder 94)
  - N, undated, 1908, 1927-1933; 61546 (Box 3, Folder 95)
  - Nafe, Gertrude, 1931-1933; 61545 (Box 3, Folder 96)
  - Nearing, Scott, undated, 1917-1933; 61544 (Box 3, Folder 97)
  - NeviNson, Henry Woodd, 1909; 61543 (Box 3, Folder 98)
  - Niebuhr, Reinhold, 1933; 61542 (Box 3, Folder 99)
  - Norman, C.H., undated, 1910; 61541 (Box 3, Folder 100)
  - North Node Book Shop, 1929-1931; 61540 (Box 3, Folder 101)
  - O, undated, 1919-1926; 61539 (Box 3, Folder 102)
  - Orage, A.R., 1931; 61538 (Box 3, Folder 103)
  - Osgood, Alivilda F., 1927-1933; 61537 (Box 3, Folder 104)
  - Osman, J.M., undated, 1926-1933; 61536 (Box 3, Folder 105)
  - P, 1908-1931, 1967; 61535 (Box 3, Folder 106)
  - Pankhurst, Christabel, 1933; 61534 (Box 3, Folder 107)
  - Pankhurst, Emmeline, 1908; 61533 (Box 3, Folder 108)
  - Pankhurst, Sylvia, 1929-1931; 61532 (Box 3, Folder 109)